<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content"><channel><title>Rafael Galdino</title><description>The Proactive iOS Developer</description><link>https://galdineris.github.io</link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 7 Dec 2020 00:16:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><pubDate>Mon, 7 Dec 2020 00:16:16 +0000</pubDate><ttl>250</ttl><atom:link href="https://galdineris.github.io/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://galdineris.github.io/projects/formworks</guid><title>Formworks</title><description>Form Builder iOS Framework</description><link>https://galdineris.github.io/projects/formworks</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Formworks aims to be the simplest way to build forms on iOS.</strong></p><p>Formworks is an Open-Source framework licensed under the MIT license developed with intention of facilitating the creation of forms on iOS application. Inspired by Server-driven UI, Formworks works by taking in JSONs describing all the components and characteristics of a form.</p><p>It uses server driven-UI to build fully funcional forms view controllers and supports real time custom user input validation as well as color customization for all the elements in the form. While working on Formworks, I've built the decoding/encoding system for the JSON files.</p><p><a href="https://github.com/MyFormworks/Formworks">Source code on GitHub</a></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://galdineris.github.io/projects/coremelysis</guid><title>Coremelyisis</title><description>ML-Powered Experience Sampling App</description><link>https://galdineris.github.io/projects/coremelysis</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Coremelysis resulted from a paper I wrote with a colleague on experience sampling on mobile devices.</strong></p><p>Ecological Momentary Assessment (EMA) are repeated sampling of behaviors in order to avoid biases and maximize ecological validity. The use of mobile applications that provide privacy to the participants and help in the process of data collection is recommended to conduct EMA-like studies. This project aims to build an application capable of applying Machine Learning On- Device (MLOD) to EMAs using Sentiment Analysis.</p><p>In this project, I was responsible for building the CoreML framework abstraction as well as implementing the Siri Shortcuts integration.</p><p><a href="https://github.com/Galdineris/Coremelysis">Source code on GitHub</a></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://galdineris.github.io/projects/chaos</guid><title>Chaos Game</title><description>WWDC20 Winner Playground on Drawing Fractals</description><link>https://galdineris.github.io/projects/chaos</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Chaos Game was one of the winners of WWDC20 Swift Student Challenge</strong></p><p>Inspired by The Chaos Game at Between Art and Science by Tom Bates, this is a simple fractal drawing SwiftPlaygrounds playground using the Chaos Game “method” and SpriteKit.</p><p>I've actually submitted the first version of this playground to WWDC19 but was rejected. After a year of studying, I've decided to refactor the code a little and fix some few bugs that would haunt me at night. To my surprise, it was accepted in this years edition of the event.</p><p><a href="https://youtu.be/LU7Z1dWoP_I">I've made this video demonstrating the playground if you would like to see it running.</a></p><p><a href="https://github.com/Galdineris/ChaosGamePlayground">Source code on GitHub</a></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://galdineris.github.io/projects/dopu</guid><title>Dõpu</title><description>tvOS Fast-Paced Game Based on Surrealism's Characteristics</description><link>https://galdineris.github.io/projects/dopu</link><pubDate>Sat, 1 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Dõpu is Fast-Paced Game based on surrealism's characteristics for the AppleTV</strong></p><p>The main character is Dõpu, that is a colorful and curious creature. You will discover many colorful skins of Dõpu while creating experience in the game.</p><p>This was a very fun project in which I've had to explore my creative side. Apart from some work on the Storyboards for the game, I was also heavly involved in the game design and was responsible for the main soundtrack of the game.</p><p><a href="https://github.com/lucasfnicolau/MagnetismTV">Source code on GitHub</a></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://galdineris.github.io/projects/mci</guid><title>MCI</title><description>Minimalist Gratitude Journaling App</description><link>https://galdineris.github.io/projects/mci</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>MCI is an simple gratitude journaling app.</strong></p><p>Loosely inspired by the play "<em>Every Brilliant Thing</em>" written by Duncan Macmillan, MCI aims to help you list everything that helps make life a little better. Its purpose is to help you get up when you are feeling a little down. A feeling, an object or even a person. If you like it, why not help future you to not forget it?</p><p>The app was made in the span of 1 month using XIB-driven UI, persistence through Core Data and Local Notifications. It was developed entirely by myself, from ideation through design and development until finally deployment at App Store. It replicates a "sheet" view controller, which is displayed constantly at the bottom of the screen and can slide into full view with swiping gestures (i.e. Apple Maps search menu or Apple Stocks detail view).</p><p><a href="https://github.com/Galdineris/MCI">Source code on GitHub</a></p>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>